Christopher Roan

Location: Elon, North Carolina 27244 (Relocating to Winston-Salem 7/30)

Email: christophertroan@gmail.com

Phone: +1 336 269 3321

About

My name is Christopher (Chris) Roan, and I am a Certified Personal Trainer and Strength and conditioning specialist. Fitness has been a major part of my life for over a decade, and I have gained a wealth of knowledge and experience that I wish to share with others. I have a Bachelor's Degree in Kinesiology with some graduate studies in physical therapy. Aside from training and coaching, I also work in data analytics and web development. My portfolio of projects can be found below. What I lack in experience or knowledge I make up for with optimism, determination, and a willingness to learn!

<u>LinkedIn</u>
<u>Data Analysis Portfolio on GitHub</u>
<u>Kaggle Profile Page</u>
<u>Tableau Profile Page</u>

Technical Skills

- 1-on-1 and group training
- Exercise programming
- Documentation medical/medical history, training session records
- Stakeholder Interaction/Client Interaction
- Data analytics R, SQL, Python, Tableau
- Web Development React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python Flask
- MS Excel Cleaning, data analysis/visualization, advanced features (VLOOKUP, Pivot Tables/Charts, dashboards)
- MS PowerPoint, Word, Project Reporting and Presentation
- Concrete Forming and Finishing
- Heavy machinery operation (skid steers, mini excavators)

Work Experience

Current employment:

Top Dasher at DoorDash

- Time employed: August 2023 to Present
- Responsibilities:
 - Time and order management organization of deliveries
 - Attention to detail ensuring the proper delivery instructions are followed
 - Customer service

Previous Employment:

Concrete Worker at O & S Concrete - Burlington, NC

- Time employed: July 2021 to July 2023
- Responsibilities:

- Setting up, pouring, and finishing residential concrete work
- Operating large machinery such as skid steers and miniature excavators
- Interacting with team members and clients to create envisioned product

Physical Therapy Technician O'Halloran Rehabilitation - Greensboro, NC

- Time Employed: March 2021 to June 2021
- Responsibilities:
 - Applying plans of care to patients in an outpatient orthopedic physical therapy clinic
 - Executing manual therapy and therapeutic exercise
 - Documenting treatment sessions

Certified Personal Trainer Fitness Together - Greensboro, NC

- Time employed: June 2019 to December 2019
- Responsibilities:
 - Meeting new clients and discussing their fitness goals
 - Providing exemplary 1-on-1/1- on-2 personal training services
 - Keeping clients motivated to meet their goals
 - Training package sales

Education

- Graduate Studies in Physical Therapy Elon, University 2020-2021
- Bachelor's Degree in Kinesiology University of North Carolina at Greensboro 2019
- Associate Degree in Science Alamance Community College 2017

Certifications and Licenses

- Certified Strength and Conditioning Specialist March 2023
 - Able to program for and coach athletes through collegiate and professional levels
 - Advanced knowledge of anatomy and biomechanics
- NSCA Certified Personal Trainer December 2021 to December 2023
 - 1-on-1 and small group personal training
 - Training package sales
- NCSF Certified Personal Trainer 2019 to 2021
 - 1-on-1 and small group personal training
 - Training package sales
- AHA BLS (CPR/AED) Certification December 2021 to December 2023
- Google Data Analytics Certificate June 2022
- Data Visualization with Tableau Specialization June 2023 to Present
- Intermediate PostgresSQL April 2023
- Database Design and Basic SQL in PostgreSQL April 2023

Awards/Additional Information

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude at UNCG
- Phi Theta Kappa Inductee (2016)
 - Honor society for collegiate scholars
- Handled and helped coach athletes at several USA Weightlifting sanctioned meets